Abigail Limpioso

(954) 756 - 3916 | alimpioso@gmail.com | Orlando, FL 32825 linkedin.com/in/alimpioso | GitHub.com/AbbyNeko | abbyneko.github.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with more than three years of programming experience working with well-known brands and companies. Designing solutions and delivering to clients promptly. Adept problem-solving ability and eager to take on new challenges. Collaborated with third-party companies by providing professional consultation and scripting.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, React, GIT, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Mongoose, Handlebars, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, APIs, Heroku, Terminal, AJAX, Restful API, ES6, JSON, Sequelize, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe PhotoShop, PHP

PROJECTS

Weather Dashboard | Full Stack Developer

Deployed: abbyneko.github.io/Weather-Dashboard | **Github:** github.com/AbbyNeko/Weather-Dashboard *A weather app that displays today's weather data by city and saves each search as a button.*

- Role: Used jQuery AJAX method to make requests to server-side APIs. Created a simple and responsive user interface using HTML and CSS. Manipulated the DOM using JavaScript to display data from OpenWeather API.
- **Tools Utilized**: HTML, CSS, JSON, Bootstrap, AJAX, HTTP GET requests, and server-side APIs

Eat-Da-Burger | Full Stack Developer

Deployed: enigmatic-hamlet-73997.herokuapp.com/ | **Github** github.com/AbbyNeko/burger *A food app that creates a list of burgers that can be added, deleted and moved to the list of Devoured burgers.*

- **Role**: Utilized Express and Node to create a server-side API to access the MySQL database. Made AJAX requests to add a burger or update a burger. All burger data, including the burger name and if the burger is devoured or not, is saved to a MySQL database. Any changes to the database are reflected on the page using Handlebars and jQuery. For example, pressing the "Devour" button will move the burger to the list on the right side of the page.
- Tools Utilized: HTML, CSS, JSON, jQuery, AJAX, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, and Express

Readable | Full Stack Developer

Deployed: apeabody007.github.io/Readable/ | **Github:** github.com/apeabody007/Readable *A social app that allows you to save books to a reading, to read and currently reading book list.*

- **Role**: Sent GET requests to the Google Books API to search for Books by title. The user can then add a book to their respective list, and the list would be updated immediately via jQuery. The user can also delete books from each list. The contents of each list per user is saved using the Web Storage API.
- Tools Utilized: HTML, CSS, JSON, BootStrap, AJAX, jQuery, Google Books API, Web Storage API

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

eMerge Technologies - Orlando, FL **Lead Developer**

02/2017 - Present

- Advanced skills in JavaScript and learned various APIs to meet the demands of multiple client projects
- Built and rigorously tested scripts to guarantee a faster and easier user workflow for many of our clients who face issues with outdated and overly complex programs that need to be improved upon or replaced
- Interacted directly with clients to assess issues, and develop out-of-the-box scripting solutions

THE SPOT @ UCF - Orlando, FL Production Assistant/Print Designer

08/2016 - 02/2017

- Delivered excellent customer service while assisting customers with printing and retail transactions
- Trained new employees on company procedures and helped them perform their duties more effectively
- Collaborated with co-workers to complete print projects while working under tight deadlines
- Designed, printed and cut business cards and store signs using Adobe Illustrator and various cutting tools

Give Back Nation - Remote **Graphic/Web Design Intern**

08/2016 - 02/2017

- Modernized the Give Back Nation site by designing web icons and graphics appealing to a wider audience
- Improved SEO and marketability of their site significantly by making web pages responsive

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate - University of Central Florida Orlando, FL

A fast paced 24-week coding boot camp program focused on gaining industry-standard programming skills.

Bachelor of Arts in Digital Media - University of Central Florida; Orlando, FL